[WOMAN SPEAKING IN
GERMAN ON INTERCOM]
The captain has turned on
the "fasten seat belt" sign.
Please make sure your seat
belts are securely fastened.
[PASSENGERS SPEAKING IN GERMAN]
I don't speak German.
I'm from Denver.
[SPEAKS IN GERMAN]
I'm from Den...
[CAPTAIN SPEAKING IN
GERMAN ON INTERCOM]
MAN: My friend, it is an electrical storm.
- I understand. Heh.
- Here. Gum?
- No. Uh, thank you.
[WOMAN SPEAKING IN GERMAN]
[SCREAMING]
[SPEAKING IN GERMAN]
[PASSENGERS SCREAMING]
[MOANING]
- Ha-ha-ha. Oh, my
God. MAN: What?
- This bed is loud.
MAN: You think?
We can't keep doing
this, sneaking around.
The department's not a
massive fan of office romance.
That policy seminar
was endless, wasn't it?
I kept staring at you. I actually
had to move my chair to stop.
- Well, I... I think Charlie knows.
- He doesn't know.
- Well, I think he does.
- If he knew, you would be transferred.
Somebody making the call whether
you and I get to live in the same city...
that's unacceptable.
Anyway, that's all just preamble
to the kicker, which is that...
I love you.
[PHONE BUZZING]
Olivia Dunham.
[CLEARS THROAT]
Yes, sir.
Of course, sir. Yes,
sir. I'm on my way.
Incident at Logan, international
flight, Charlie's on his way.
[PHONE RINGS]
Agent Scott.
Olivia Dunham, FBI.
We got a flight out of Hamburg.
Hundred and forty-seven passengers.
Towers lost contact
three hours in.
Thought it might've been
electrical interference.
They entered our
airspace radio-silent.
Navy then scrambles
two F-18's for escort.
They reported stains in the
windows, no signs of life aboard the jet.
White House approved
a CDC request...
for the jet not to be
opened until they arrive.
No signs of life? Who
was flying the plane?
Logan's one of the first airports
with the PEARL autopilot system.
Plane landed itself right on time,
unlike every flight I've ever taken.
Let me assure you, we'd be
happy to treat you as family too.
Good old NTSB. They all
like to think they're cops.
- Agent Scott.
- Agent Francis. Agent Dunham.
Whatever the hell McNeary
saw through that window...
it made him throw up
in front of his whole unit.
MAN: Excuse me.
So, what's going on here?
Some sort of accident?
GUARD: Tarmac's closed.
Nothing you have to worry about, sir.
- All right. GUARD:
Move it along.
I'll do that. Thanks.
Although this is
a joint task force...
you are all now reporting to the
Department of Homeland Security.
I'm Special Agent
in Charge Broyles.
DC has sent me here to
make sure we get results.
Standard level-four HAZMAT
suits are required to go in.
Members from each agency
on the starting line as follows:
CIA, Baronoff. FBI, Charlie
Francis and John Scott.
Everyone else stand by.
Okay, people, let's move.
OLIVIA: Sir, Olivia Dunham,
FBI inter-agency liaison.
BROYLES: Liaison on
an inter-agency task force.
Gotta love that.
Kind of like powdered
sugar on a glazed donut.
Excuse me, if I'm gonna
do my job effectively...
I like my information
first-hand.
That's not redundancy,
that's accountability.
I know exactly who you are.
You want in, liaison? Suit up.
AGENT: What kind of terrorism is this?
- Who says it's terrorism?
REPORTER [ON TV]: Sources tell us
the plane was deliberately set ablaze...
by the CDC after all passengers'
remains had been removed...
leading to speculation
of hazardous...
AGENT 1: Seat 21-A: John Rosenbloom.
AGENT 2:43-B: Ellie Sampson.
AGENT 1: Car salesman.
Criminal history's negative.
AGENT 2: Intelligence
checks negative.
Have we reviewed
video from Hamburg?
We need to see if any passengers
were showing signs of illness.
We need names.
On its way, Dawson. What the hell's
taking so long with the black box?
- Police tell me that terminal shut down.
- Been down since 0400.
- You got any more questions?
- Who's point from CDC on the bone...?
Agent Paley, you
want his home number?
No, but I'd like the whole
report, and not just this...
We're on that too, liaison.
We don't think what happened
was a result of the in-flight movie.
Back Bay PD got a call at 0300 from
a guard on duty at a storage facility.
He saw two, and I quote,
"suspicious Middle Eastern men"...
- handing a white guy a briefcase.
- Liaison.
Take it. Go find out.
Take what, that? You're
telling me that's my assignment?
Yeah, honey, would you mind?
REPORTER: The decision was made to burn
the plane only after it was determined...
OLIVIA: Petty bastard.
He's pissed his best friend sexually
assaulted three Marine privates.
- I'm the bad guy, I put him away.
- Broyles is an idiot.
You're smarter, you're stronger,
you're much better looking. He's jealous.
What?
You said you loved
me. In the motel.
Yeah.
That was a big deal.
Yeah, well, you didn't say
anything back so I just let it go.
I've been sort of bad
at this for a long time.
Until you.
I wanted to say I love you too.
Let's go check
the trash together.
- Empty.
- Acetylene? Propane?
No. Ammonia.
- What are you doing?
I'm a federal agent.
[ANIMAL GIBBERING]
We need to get a chem
transport team out here now.
I'm on it.
[PHONE BEEPING]
No signal.
Freeze. FBI.
JOHN: I have a
gun. I will shoot.
- John? JOHN [OVER
PHONE]: We got a runner.
- Keep him alive.
- I'm on my way.
[PHONE DIALING]
JOHN: Hands in the air.
- John!
[SCREAMS]
DOCTOR: You were very
lucky today, Agent Dunham.
Your wounds could have
easily been much more severe.
Agent Scott wasn't as fortunate.
While he survived
the initial blast...
Agent Scott was exposed to some
synthetic chemical compounds.
Work that was done
in the labs you found.
He's not contagious, but
until we understand more...
it's better not to introduce
any additional contaminants.
We haven't been able to identify
the substance that's affecting him.
The CDC has
sent in specialists...
but, well, they've never seen
anything like what's happening here.
We've put Agent Scott
in a drug-induced coma.
His temperature has
been lowered significantly...
to try and slow the progress.
I'm sorry, Agent Dunham.
It's me. Liaison.
I found a connection
between the Hamburg flight...
and what's happened
to Agent Scott.
His name's Walter Bishop.
He's a scientific researcher
from Cambridge, born in '46.
Harvard-educated,
post-grad at Oxford and MIT.
Look at the
experiments in the '70s.
Dr. Bishop might have
information that might tell us...
what happened aboard that
plane and save Scott's life.
Says the guy's been at
St. Claire's for 17 years.
I saw that. An assistant
was killed in his lab.
Rumors about Dr. Bishop
using humans as guinea pigs.
He was charged with manslaughter,
but deemed mentally unfit.
- Why're you so sure he's worth our time?
- Why are you so sure he's not?
Listen, you and I got
off on the wrong foot.
If my past job performance as U.S.
Marine Special Investigator offends you...
Well, yeah, it does.
A man who serves
his country 30 years...
has a few drinks, a
lapse in judgment...
A lapse in judgment that will haunt
three women for the rest of their lives.
But that's not
tonight's business, is it?
Look, D.C. has tasked
me to make sure...
that our reaction to Flight
627 is beyond reproach.
Now, it says here...
in 1991 the glorious state of
Massachusetts forbade Dr. Bishop...
from having any visitors, with
the exception of immediate family.
From where I sit, barging into a mental
institution waving the Patriot Act...
Which is what you'd need.
And demanding face
time with some old lab rat...
who you think might be behind the
most terrifying terror I can imagine...
I'm coming to you with a lead,
and your personal resentment...
You're wasting your breath and my time.
Do you understand "immediate family"?
You wanna question Dr. Bishop, go
find his next of kin, have them escort you.
Talk to Bishop, uncover something
substantial, and I will have your back.
Until then, I am not so convinced.
Now, can you handle that?
He does have a son.
Is the son local too?
Not exactly.
MAN: So this guy's Walter Bishop's
son. OLIVIA: His name's Peter Bishop.
He's a high school dropout. IQ at
190, which is 50 points north of genius.
Misfit. Nomad. Hasn't kept
a job longer than two months.
He's been a wildland
fireman, cargo pilot...
and, briefly, a college
chemistry professor.
He falsified a
degree from MIT...
and even managed to get a few
papers published before he was found out.
Sounds like a
massive pain in the ass.
PETER: My resume
is hardly traditional.
Around these parts, traditional
increasingly means irrelevant.
Hundred billion sunk into infrastructure,
you can barely keep lights on.
You need someone to oversee
construction on 600 miles of pipeline...
to carry crude between
your fields and the port.
A job well outside the Green Zone, I
might add, while I'm still alive to do so.
Someone who has a handle on
the laws of hydrodynamic resistance.
The heat exchange
in oil-mixture flows.
Someone who can
work with mixed integers.
You're gonna have to resize as
you work across uneven terrain.
That is if you wanna keep
down construction costs.
[MEN SPEAKING IN FARSI]
I also speak Farsi.
And 600,000 all-in sounds fair.
Peter Bishop?
Olivia Dunham, I'm with the FBI.
- Okay.
- You've heard of Flight 627?
- The Hamburg flight.
- You may be able to help us with that.
Ha, ha. No, I think
you got the wrong guy.
Your father is Walter Bishop.
Last time somebody asked
me that it was an accusation.
We're looking to speak with him.
Due to his current status,
only you can provide us access.
And what possible
help could that man be?
And what is it exactly
you're expecting me to do?
Hop on a plane with
you to Massachusetts?
I just got here, honey.
I can have you on a return
flight here in four days...
Let me save you the time.
I'd rather stay here in Iraq.
That's how much I
wanna see my father.
I'm going to beg you as
one human being to another.
Your father may be able to
save someone who's dying.
Someone I care about very much.
Sweetheart, we all care
about someone who's dying.
I can't help you. I'm sorry.
I know why you're here.
I have your file.
[CHUCKLES]
What file?
The one the FBI
would say doesn't exist.
And it has everything.
Where you've been.
What you're running from.
And what you need
while you're here.
So either you come with me...
or I let certain people
know your whereabouts.
When do we leave?
OLIVIA: Did the doctors
say anything else? Yeah.
Thanks, Charlie.
[OLIVIA CLEARS THROAT]
Let me ask you something.
My father. Not my favorite.
He is without a doubt
the most self-absorbed...
twisted, abusive, brilliant,
myopic son-of-a-bitch on the planet.
So he was a chemist,
that much I already know.
He worked out of a
basement lab in Harvard...
doing research for a
toothpaste company.
I know there was an
accident at the lab one night.
My father was arrested.
Beginning the first truly
peaceful period in our home.
But here's the thing, Olivia.
My gut tells me that your friend's
life, the one hanging in the balance...
not gonna be saved
by a tube of toothpaste.
He worked out of Harvard.
But not on toothpaste.
He was part of a classified U.S.
Army experimental program...
called Kelvin Genetics.
They gave him the resources
to do whatever work he wanted...
which was primarily in an
area called Fringe Science.
When you say Fringe Science,
you mean pseudoscience.
I suppose. Things like
mind control, teleportation...
astral projection, invisibility,
genetic mutation, reanimation...
Excuse me for a sec.
Reanimation? Really?
So you're telling me what?
My father was Dr. Frankenstein?
You know what? Why
don't you go on ahead.
GUARD: Dr. Bishop. Special
day. You have a visitor.
Hello.
I knew someone
would come eventually.
OLIVIA: Dr. Bishop.
Dr. Bishop?
And you said this was... This
was... When did this happen?
The incident on the plane
happened four days ago.
- Agent Scott was injured the next day.
- The dermis already indurated?
- Translucent? Muscular tissue visible?
- On Scott?
You mean, can you see
through his skin? Yes.
Oh, that's not good.
To see through the
skin, it's, uh... It's tricky.
- It's advanced like that...
- What's happening to him?
Can it be reversed?
What is it?
They...
They have this
horrible pudding here.
Butterscotch pudding
on Mondays. It's dreadful.
It's Thursday.
Oh?
Oh, ha, ha. That's
fantastic news.
It can be reversed.
Oh, what happened
to your colleague.
Years ago I worked
with lab animals...
and some of them were
afflicted, but were saved.
So do you remember what to do?
This place, their
choice of therapies has...
[GRUMBLES]
Dr. Bishop?
You came here today with my son.
I'm not allowed visitors, you
see, except immediate family...
and unless the
order's been lifted...
then it's a simple
if-then formula.
If you are here, then so is he.
I would so much...
so very much like to see him.
So much.
He asked for you.
Thanks, sweetheart. I
really appreciate that.
Hey, I didn't tell
him you were here.
And call me sweetheart one
more time. I'd really like that.
Hello, Walter.
I thought you'd be fatter.
You thought I would be fatter?
Excellent. First words. Perfect.
No, as a boy, you were rounder.
I was until the summer
before high school.
- Not that I'd expect you to remember.
- May I see?
What are you doing?
Take your hands off.
Pupils are good.
They're good. Thank goodness.
How advanced is your
colleague's condition?
[STAMMERS] Which
is something that I...
I'm unable to deduce without
a firsthand examination.
I must see Mr. Scott myself...
which I am unable to do...
while under present law...
unless signed out
by a legal guardian...
who must be, once
again, a relative.
What are you asking me to...?
- No. Guardian? No. Forget it.
- He'll do it.
- No, I will not do it.
- One phone call. That's all it takes.
Do you want me to make it? Because
I've got my phone in my pocket.
Now it's out of my pocket.
You wanted my father,
now you've got my father...
which falls under the category
of, "Be careful what you wish for."
Sweetheart.
REPORTER [ON RADIO]:
Every effort is being made...
to understand what
happened on Flight 627.
OLIVIA: Dr. Bishop,
I was curious.
Did anyone else ever
have access to your work?
Well, uh, the assistants
had bits and pieces.
God, I suppose.
I suppose the only one that really
knew what I was doing was Belly.
- Who?
- Belly. William Bell.
- He and I shared the lab.
- William Bell?
You shared your lab with the
founder of Massive Dynamic?
I'm sorry. I don't know what
that is, Massive Dynamic.
Nothing, really. Just a tiny
little company. That's perfect.
One becomes one of the
wealthiest men on the planet.
The other guy becomes an
institutionalized psychopath.
- Oh!
- What? What happened?
I just pissed myself.
- Excellent.
- Just a squirt.
CHARLIE: I just
got your message.
- How is John?
- Worse.
CDC says the flight was
caused by a synthetic compound...
which is like saying rain is
caused by a wet compound.
They've run tests on John, but
haven't come back with anything.
- What about Bishop?
- Left to right? Insane.
And irritating and
also my only hope.
Listen. I need to
question William Bell.
- Could you set that up for me?
- William Bell?
- Massive Dynamic William Bell?
- He and Bishop used to share a lab.
You're kidding.
Dr. Bishop?
Is there ginger
ale? Any ginger ale?
I haven't had
some in a long time.
I miss it.
Can we please get some ginger
ale for the doctor, Agent Farnsworth?
Sure.
Whoa! Stop. Right now. Stop.
Does this not concern you?
Let him go.
Petri dish.
Quick. Please.
Good.
I need to take this
to my lab right away.
- Your what?
- Kresge Building basement, Harvard.
We should leave.
I have my sample.
Your lab was shut
down after you left.
I'm sorry?
Wake up. It's gone.
No.
No, no, no.
No, no, no, no, no, no.
Walter, there is no lab.
- It's a perfect...
- No.
Damn you. Damn you.
We need to get him
back immediately.
- Liaison, when did you get back?
- I need your help.
I want you to know I've successfully
had Dr. Walter Bishop released...
from St. Claire's, and he requires
the use of his old laboratory.
- I'm sorry, what?
- Kresge Building, Harvard. Basement.
The university's been using it
for storage for the last 17 years.
It would be nice to think that
your tenacity in this case...
is a by-product of a remarkable
and robust professionalism.
But I can't help but wonder...
if there wasn't something going
on between you and Agent Scott.
Get the lab for Bishop.
So much. So much happened here.
And so much is about to.
OLIVIA: Dr. Bishop, I've ordered a
standard forensics work package.
- Is there anything else you need?
- Um...
Optical coherence
tomograph for flesh study.
Two thousand pounds of silicon.
At least five anonymous blood
samples from volunteer donors.
A micro-organism detector,
NASA-grade, of course.
- There's still NASA, yes?
- Yes.
She's still here! Oh,
this tank was the best.
And... And a
two-year-old Bostaurus.
- A what? PETER: A cow.
- He wants a cow. WALTER:
Pure-bred, not cross-bred.
This is important. Mature
weight, 850 pounds.
Internal fat average, 2.37.
Is he joking?
Genetically, humans and cows are
separated by only a couple lines of DNA.
- It's an ethical test subject.
- Where'd you learn that?
- MIT?
- No, actually.
I picked that up reading books.
You should try it
some time. It's fun.
- Get him the cow.
- Fantastic, thank you.
The only thing better
than a cow is a human.
Unless you need milk.
Then you really need a cow.
[COW MOOS]
Coffee?
Thanks.
Tell me. What else
did that file say?
About yours truly.
How bad was it?
I'm not at liberty
to discuss it.
[CHUCKLES]
You go ahead and
liberate yourself...
because I'm here now, so I kind of
feel like I deserve the truth, don't you?
There was no file.
- I needed you back here.
- So, what? You were bluffing?
- I was desperate.
- I'm usually good at reading people.
- That's what I do.
- I could see you were in trouble.
- Anyone could see that.
- So I could have stayed.
Ha, ha.
I could've stayed in Iraq.
You know, a car bomb went
off this morning in Kirkuk.
- You might just owe me a thank you.
- Ha.
Yeah, well. I owe a lot.
Yeah, I figured.
- Mafia?
- Ha-ha-ha.
A guy named Big Eddie.
You owe money to a
guy nicknamed Big Eddie?
No, I owe money to a guy named
Big Eddie. He had it legally changed.
And the thing is, I'm not even a
gambler. I mean, I never was, it just...
- A couple years ago I went a bit crazy.
- I thought you were a genius.
- You must've had a system.
- Of course there was a system.
The house was cheating,
but try telling them that.
WALTER: In '72,
during Vietnam...
the DOD's biochem division had
us working on a leprotic contagion...
for possible use
against the Vietcong.
It's possible that whatever
affected that plane...
may have been
derived from that work.
What about John?
What's infecting him is
merely a chemical reaction...
to the raw laboratory ingredients,
not the finished contagion.
- We can synthesize a counter-agent.
- So you can help...
Don't do that. Don't
give her false hope.
There's no false,
it's not false. It's real.
I could help, yes, if I
had a precise inventory...
of what was in that storage
facility when it detonated...
We don't have it. It
all went up. Everything.
The suspect, who might
have answers, got away.
And John was the only
one who saw his face.
So how long does he have left?
Current rate of crystallization,
cellular degradation...
- How long?
- Twenty-four hours.
His brain will no longer
be able to oxygenate itself.
I'm so sorry...
that I can't offer you a
less dangerous solution.
- What do you mean?
- Didn't I mention it?
Whatever you think
you said, you didn't say.
The synaptic transfer system,
the shared dream state.
What do you mean,
shared dream state?
The human brain generates
a quantifiable electric field.
I posited in 1976
that it is possible...
to synchronize the fields
of two distinct minds...
to allow the sharing of information
across the unconscious state.
Like a string
between two tin cans.
And you know what's great about
that is that it's completely insane.
You're saying I can
talk to John in a coma...
and he can tell me what
the suspect looks like?
- It's not an exact science.
PETER: It's not even science.
- Have you done this before?
- I have used this technique...
to extract information
from a corpse, once.
You can do that if they
haven't been dead for six hours.
Right, because after six
hours, they're really dead.
You could access his memories.
Assuming there's no brain damage.
Of course, you'd have to have
an electromagnetic probe...
placed in the
base of your skull...
whilst immersed without
clothing in the old tank.
And you'd be heavily drugged.
- What sort of drugs?
- A mix of...
Ketamine, Neurontin,
Lysergic Acid Diethylamide.
That last one is LSD
by the way. Acid?
It'd take a few hours. I'd
need your help to synthesize it.
- If it's not too much trouble.
- Sure, sounds fun.
The man who was released
from the mental institution...
wants to give you an overdose,
stick a rod in your head...
and put you naked into
a rusty tank of water.
No, I don't want to.
No, I'd rather not.
I'm just saying I can.
Okay, Olivia. Heh.
Excuse me. You're
obviously under severe duress.
You haven't slept since Iraq,
the man you care about might die.
- But I'm telling you, that will kill you.
- You don't understand the procedure.
John would do it for me.
Set it up. I'll get DHS
authorization to bring John here.
This is unbelievable.
This is insane.
He is insane. And you're
insane for following him.
Excellent. Let's make some LSD.
OLIVIA: Put him over here.
ASTRID: Salt'll make you float.
Charlie, did you get me
in to see William Bell?
Massive Dynamic isn't exactly
being forthcoming or courteous.
And apparently William
Bell is out of the country.
What's this?
A sweet little memo
from their general counsel.
- Bell doesn't wanna talk?
- Or he's the head...
- of a 50-billion-dollar corporation.
- Screw this.
I wanna drive a tank through
Bell's office. Find out what he knows.
I know you do, but I'm
here to tell you the bad news.
It's gonna be 48 hours
till we get a court order.
You should probably
strip to your underwear.
Hello.
What the hell was that?
Charlie, we don't have 48
hours. I need you to get to Bell.
If Walter fails, Bell could
be the only one to save us.
What...? Livvy, what's
happening here?
You've cleared all
this with Broyles?
- Somewhat.
- "Somewhat" doesn't sound good.
[MOOS]
- Is that a cow?
- Yeah, that's Gene.
Listen, Charlie, I need you to
promise me you'll do whatever you can.
Of course, you know that.
Hey, be careful.
My God.
WALTER: Now, where was I?
Could you tilt your
head forward please.
I still think that this is
deeply irresponsible...
and believe me, I would know.
This is an anesthetic.
I feel normal. Working.
Yeah, because bootlegging smack in the
basement is just the picture of normalcy.
[GASPS]
I got you. I got you.
I hope your guy is worth it.
And this...
will rip open your
consciousness.
Listen. In case you
don't come back...
I just wanted to say,
before we do this...
how much I appreciate
what you've done.
There are so many things
you lose in a place like that.
You lose being trusted.
It's strange how important
that is, once it's gone.
If you want to watch,
you can come closer.
- Do you work here?
- Yeah, I'm Astrid Farnsworth.
- Assistant to Agent Dunham.
- Who?
Oh, yes. I'm Walter...
- Bishop. Walter Bishop.
- Yes, thank you.
Don't mention it.
These are her brain rhythms.
More important than most people know
regarding cerebral regional interaction.
Critical.
And, uh... And these are his.
As the drugs take effect...
the probes will synchronize
the electrical signals from both.
That's what the brain
is, an electrical router.
Should be able to be
interpreted by the other.
Ha, ha. Yeah.
Simple, really,
like making taffy.
And when the rhythms are in sync,
they should be in the same place...
so to speak.
So, what do we do now?
Now we wait.
What was that?
Hello?
I think I'm here.
I think I'm here. I'm here.
John?
That's my uncle's kayak.
Is that you?
JOHN: Olivia.
John.
- What's happening?
WALTER: It's fine.
- She's all right?
- She's fine.
- You're sure?
- Look.
I was just thinking about you.
What was that?
Nothing.
John.
You were hurt.
I don't remember.
Think.
The storage units.
I feel cold.
I need you to remember.
Remember what?
What you saw.
I need you to show me his face.
Why?
So I can save you.
Please try.
Try and remember.
Yes, this is right.
This is right.
JOHN: We got a
runner in the back.
We need him alive.
OLIVIA: I can't see his face.
[YELLS]
I saw him. I saw John
get hurt. I was there.
I was there. I saw... I saw him.
[PANTING]
What do you mean,
you saw him? Where?
I told you not to ask me that.
This is him. This
is the suspect.
- He looks like this.
- Send me the image.
- I'll put it through the database.
- Have you slept? You look like crap.
No primary matches
for criminal record.
Crosscheck state driver's license
files. Send this image to local hospitals.
Agent Dunham,
take a look at this.
Oh, my God, this is him.
- He was a passenger on Flight 627.
- I don't understand.
He couldn't have been
at the storage place.
- Charlie, I saw him there.
AGENT: Hold on, guys.
Morgan Steig was
passenger number 108.
His emergency
contact: Richard Steig.
- You're telling me he has a
twin? AGENT: Yeah. No address.
Only a history of employment.
CHARLIE: What?
- Richard Steig's last employer.
OLIVIA: I was hoping to
speak with William Bell.
NINA: I'm Nina Sharp,
executive director.
I only have a few minutes.
OLIVIA: Our primary suspect
is a former employee of yours...
Richard Steig, who may have
used research from your company...
to develop a
self-eradicating airborne toxin.
We don't know why or for whom...
but it appears he was willing
to sacrifice his own brother.
Whatever killed those people got
on board through his insulin pen.
So do you wanna talk to me?
Danielle...
please assemble everything we have
on Richard Steig for Agent Dunham here.
I remember Richard Steig.
He worked in our
weapons-systems research lab.
He was caught three months ago trying
to leave with classified information.
He was terminated. We referred
his name to the justice department.
We have done our due
diligence, Agent Dunham...
and if you choose to
drag our company...
and Dr. Bell's name
into this matter...
you will be hearing
from our attorneys.
- How long have you worked for Dr. Bell?
- Sixteen years.
I owe Massive Dynamic my life,
and that is not an exaggeration.
I was a runner most of my life.
In the '97 Boston Marathon,
I felt strangely tired.
One day at the office,
Dr. Bell noticed my discomfort...
and insisted I go
for a CAT scan.
Cancer.
It spread so severely...
I had to have my arm
amputated that week.
That first scanner that found my
cancer was built by this company.
The robotic assist tools
used in my surgery...
the drugs I took afterwards...
were developed and
manufactured by Massive Dynamic...
and my replacement limb
was designed by Bell himself.
Everything we have
on Richard Steig.
Do you believe that Steig
may be part of The Pattern?
I'm sorry, part of the...
Part of the pattern?
Oh, I assumed you had clearance.
Well, I'm cleared to know
whatever you're cleared to know.
Apparently not.
Suffice to say that we've reached a
point where science and technology...
have advanced at such an
exponential rate for so long...
it may be way beyond our
ability to regulate and control them.
You should know what you're
getting into, Agent Dunham.
I would say this to
my own daughter:
Be careful...
and good luck.
[WALTER LAUGHING]
- And this is a show for children?
- Yeah, it's huge.
[PHONE RINGS]
Surprisingly profound for
a narrative about a sponge.
Crazy house.
I just landed at
Logan. I'm on my way.
I think we located our suspect.
Hold on a second. You found
the guy? The guy from your dream?
I'm picking you up. I need your
father to get information he needs...
so he can make the cure. I
need you in case your father's...
Say no more. Meet you out front.
AGENT 1: Clear!
AGENT 2: Clear! AGENT 3: Clear!
AGENT 1: In the back!
[ANIMALS SCREECHING]
WALTER: I'd like to
check your blood pressure.
Why don't you check your own
blood pressure? Mine's fine, thanks.
Your skin tone suggests you might
be suffering from arterial hypertension.
Don't tell me what
I'm suffering from.
And there are no visible
signs of hypertension.
When this is over,
please don't send me back.
- I don't want to go back.
- Look, Walter...
This experience, you...
You woke me up again, and, heh.
- You can't put me back to sleep.
- It was hardly my idea, any of it.
Whatever punishment
you think I deserve...
I swear, I have
already endured it...
seventeen years.
Please...
son.
[DOOR CREAKS]
Hey!
- Hey!
- What?
Hey! He's in the alley!
- Can I get out of the car?
- Stay right there, Walter.
[HORNS HONKING]
[GRUNTS]
We've got some
questions for you.
OLIVIA: U.S. Code 1 1 1 1:
murder of 147 passengers.
U.S. Code 2332A: use of
weapons of mass destruction.
U.S. Code 2332B: an act of
terrorism transcending national borders.
U.S. Code 1 1 13: attempted
murder of a federal agent.
You want immunity?
I want a detailed account of
all the synthetic chemicals...
you had in that
storage facility.
Write them down...
and then we can talk
about an agreement.
I have nothing to say.
Walter, stay here.
Where are you...?
The compound affecting Agent
Scott, it's water-soluble, right?
We might not know what it
is, but we know what it does...
so if I wanted to...
I could extract the
contaminated fluids from his body.
That would allow me to slip it
to you whenever I wanted to.
In your food...
cup of coffee...
the toilet.
Nobody would ever
know how it happened.
The only problem is, the
woman who was just in here...
that's her friend who's dying...
so I just don't have
that kind of time.
No.
[SCREAMS]
- Tell me the chemicals now.
- Hey, stop. You can't.
- You can't do that.
- No, no. You can't do that.
I want the names of the
chemicals. I'm gonna count to one.
- One.
- Aah!
The active toxin was a
magnesium-based ethylene glycol.
- I understand. You're not listening.
WALTER: An ethylene glycol...
- with an organophosphate trigger.
- Walter, stop.
His blood won't be able to
absorb it before side effects kill him.
So you're saying what? We synthesize
a calcium gluconate in a thiamine base?
- Yes, exactly.
- We can't. We need more of his blood.
- We have none.
- Not true. Agents are required...
to set up a backup blood
supply in case we're wounded.
- Autologous transfusion.
Brilliant. PETER: Transfusion.
We create the antidote and
dissolve it into Scott's stored blood.
If we transfuse him intravenously,
his body won't be overwhelmed.
WALTER: A-plus, boy.
Well done. Let's begin.
- So I got the lab.
- Heh.
Yeah, I know you did.
Thanks.
How's it going downstairs?
Uh...
Bishop says it'll be a while,
but that it's looking auspicious.
That was his word.
- What?
- You've done some solid work here:
Locating Bishop...
getting him out, finding a
way to get him to work with you.
- We're impressed.
- Who's "we"?
What happened on that plane might
be part of something more dangerous...
- than just simple terrorism.
- "Simple" terrorism?
In the past nine months, there
have been three dozen incidents...
like the Hamburg flight.
John Thompson, normal
kid, went missing back in '98...
reappeared last month halfway
around the world. Hadn't aged a day.
In the past few months,
46 other children...
who went missing that same
year turn up. Same story.
Fisherman off the coast of Sri
Lanka reports a low-flying plane...
emitting a high-pitched frequency
that blows out all their windows.
An hour later, same spot, an
8.7 subsurface earthquake...
creates a tsunami
that kills 83,000 people.
- So why are you telling me...?
- This man:
Patient in Lisbon who woke up
after years in a coma, began writing.
Just numbers. They turn out to
be exact, real-time coordinates...
of our carrier battle
groups in the Pacific.
Intel that's classified
above top secret.
So how is that even possible?
Come work for me. I'll
get you the clearance...
- Oh, stop.
- There's more you need to hear.
- You must not have heard me.
- They're calling the events The Pattern...
as if someone's experimenting,
only the world is their lab.
- You've seen. You know.
- I don't wanna know.
- I have a job.
- This is a more important job.
Anything, anybody
you need, you can have.
I like the job I've got,
and the man I do it with...
which you seem to have
deduced on your own.
Look around. You see all these
people, going about their lives...
no idea what's happening around
them, what they're in the middle of?
I just wanna go back to before.
Dunham...
I don't think you can.
[GASPS]
He's up. He's awake.
Olivia, Olivia, he's
awake. He's conscious.
John?
John? Can you hear me, baby?
Baby?
I had a dream about you.
Change of clothes
for Agent Scott.
His vitals are
surprisingly strong.
- So, um, how long does he have to stay?
- Until the melanocytes in his skin...
have regenerated, but that
shouldn't be more than a week.
He owes you his life.
We owe each other.
What room is Steig in?
I told you everything
I know, didn't I?
I gave you the names of all the
synthetics I used in the compound.
Don't worry, our
immunity agreement holds.
But there's still more to talk about,
like why you killed your brother...
- and who you're selling your work to.
- Who says I was selling it?
I was threatened by
a guy from your office.
You think I'm lying?
I swear to God.
I can prove it.
- I recorded the conversation.
- Where's the recording?
I buried it.
STEIG [ON
RECORDER]: Who is this?
MAN [ON RECORDER]: We
had an exchange agreement.
STEIG: Mm. There
have been other bidders.
Today, the airplane,
was a demonstration.
MAN: You've drawn
unwarranted attention...
something we can't
afford to be connected with.
You're not selling to anyone else.
You do that, we will come after you.
- I will come after you.
STEIG: You're threatening me?
After seeing what I'm willing
to do to my own brother?
MAN: Let me assure you, we'd
be happy to treat you as family too.
Let me assure you, we'd be
happy to treat you as family too.
Special Agent Scott.
Yes, sir. Go right ahead.
Charlie, I need two agents posted
outside Agent Scott's room now.
- Check on Steig. CHARLIE
[OVER PHONE]: I'm on it.
OLIVIA: I'm five minutes away.
We need this place locked down.
This is Dunham.
Agent ID 52776...
in pursuit of blue SUV
heading south on Fenway.
Need immediate assist.
[SIREN WAILING]
[GROANING]
Ask yourself...
why.
Why Broyles sent you...
to the storage facility.
Why you?
I don't understand.
Who are you working for?
John, tell me.
Tell me more, John.
CHARLIE: I knew him
just as long as you did.
I'm sorry.
Job isn't what it
was 10 years ago.
We're supposed
to protect a world...
where one breath of the wrong air
can incinerate you from the inside out.
I mean, how do
we protect people...
when corporations have higher
security clearances than we do...
when we're not fully briefed on half
the things that we're investigating?
You know, when the truth...
The truth is...
we're obsolete.
Take me back to the lab.
Can I talk to you, please?
Yeah. I'll be back in a second.
I, uh... I'm sure you're anxious to
get as far away from here as possible.
To Iraq or Afghanistan or
countless other out-of-reach places...
but, uh, I'm here to tell you
your father needs to stay.
Which means you need to, too.
Are you okay?
Now, I know that you
have countless reasons...
as to why this is a
nonstarter for you...
but, uh, your father is a good man.
He's not the monster you think he is.
You're good with him,
despite what you think.
And you're the only
one who speaks Walter.
We take him back to St.
Claire's, and it's all over.
- Where's John?
- I can talk to the agency...
and get them to
clear your debts.
I can take care of my own
debts. But what just happened?
Where is John?
I'm not gonna use false threats
with you anymore. I don't need to.
The threats are real.
After you left, my father sat
down and started talking...
and he was remarkably lucid.
He told me about the work
he and William Bell had done.
And that incident...
What happened on the
plane is just the beginning.
Which makes every part of me feel
like I gotta get the hell out of Boston.
WALTER: Are we leaving?
Are we leaving?
- How long has he been
dead? NURSE: Five hours.
Question him.
[ENGLISH SDH]